Baatchia Riyadh

Location: Setif, Algeria Phone: (+213) 213 657 73 50 82 Email: Baatchia Riyadh@protonmail.com

Portfolio: Riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio-website-react

Full Stack Web developer with a master's degree in Computer Science. I have several years of experience in Web and Desktop development, focusing on frontend development (React) as well as back-End development (NodeJS). I am self-motivated person, fast learner and open to new challenges for the development of my skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SIRIUS SERVICES - ABB PARTNER

Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

September 2020 - September 2022

- Developed various scripts to automate a variety of repetitive task to increase productivity and efficiency.
- Designed and develop internal software applications for addressing company problems and needs.

FREELANCING Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

2019 – September 2020

Designed and developed some simple applications for local small business

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria
July 2019

Masters in Computer Engineering,

- Graduated with B grading (grading is decided relative to other students).
- Developed a Full stack Web Application to facilitate the management of the Scientific Council of the institute.

ELECTRICITY AND GAS DISTRIBUTION ADMINISTRATION

INTERNSHIP

Oum El Bouaghi, Algeria 24/03/2018 - 05/04/2018

- Was responsible for daily backing up customers database.
- Was giving a basic walk-through on the IT department daily operations.

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

License in Electrical and Electronics Engineering,

July 2017

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- Web: HTML/CSS/JavaScript, NodeJS, ReactJS, ExpressJS, Apollo GraphQL, ElectronJS.
- Desktop: C#, .NET, WPF, XAML, WinForms
- Data Bases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL
- Other: Rust

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Proficient in MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Fluent in English, Arabic, and little bit of French